theredddesk.org 2019-06-13

# Privacy / Cookie Notice | The REDD Desk

Last updated: 8 March, 2016 

This privacy / cookie notice tells you what to expect when you visit theredddesk.org and the information we collect about our visitors.

## Who we are

This website is owned and managed by [Global Canopy Programme](http://www.globalcanopy.org/) (GCP) a tropical forest think-tank. Global Canopy Programme is a registered UK charity (no 1089110) based at 23 Park End Street, Oxford, OX1 1 HU, England.

### We gather two types of information from you:

  * Information your web browser gives us, such as your computer's IP address, your screen resolution and your geographic location. We also monitor your use of the website by seeing which pages you visit and how long you spend on them. We send this information to Google's "Google Analytics" service so that we can measure how effectively our website is at giving you the information you're after.
  * Information you actively give us, which includes joining our REDD network, giving feedback on our website content or messages you send us. We use this information to deal with your request and never share this information with anyone outside of our business.

## What we do with the information your computer gives us

When someone visits theredddesk.org we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behavior patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone.

We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this and ask you. We will make it clear when we ask for personal information and explain what we intend to do with it.

## What we do with the information you give us

The details from any contact us enquiry or share your knowledge feedback sent to us, may be entered onto our in house contact management system for the purpose of effective processing. We will only use the information supplied to us to deal with the enquiry and any subsequent issues. Your contact details will continue to be stored, for historic reference, for an appropriate time period and will be retained in a secure environment and access to it will be restricted according to the ‘need to know’ principle.

Your email will only be used for the purpose of replying to your initial enquiry, and will not be included in any mass marketing or information communication, unless you have opted in (by ticking a box on this or a previous communication) to agree to become part of our network. 

People who join our GCP REDD network agree to receive periodic emails from Global Canopy Programme which cover REDD and/or tropical forest related issues. At any time an individual in the network can unsubscribe from email communications through the link in each email communication or by contacting us.

We use a third party email broadcast provider, I-Contact, to deliver our mass email newsletters. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies including clear gifs to help us monitor and improve our future email communications.

## How we use cookies

"Cookies" are small files which your web browser transfers to your computer when you visit a site.  They are widely used in order to make websites work, or to work more efficiently, as well as providing information to the owners of the site.

Like many websites, we use cookies to help us monitor your use of the website. These cookies are used by Google Analytics so that we know when you've visited one page and then another.  We also use cookies if you login to our website with a username and password we've given you.

### What cookies do we use?

Each cookie we use has a unique name which you can use to identify where it came from. Below is a list of the subject areas these cookis are based around and further details on their use:

  * Some features of our site use Javascript. We set a has_js cookie if you have javascript enabled, so we can give you the best possible experience.
  * Our interactive map in our countries section is provided by a third party provider [cloudmade.com](http://cloudmade.com/) has its own unique cookies.
  * Google translate also creates its own set of cookies.
  * Our twitter news feed on the home page of our website also has its own unique cookies.
  * Google Analytics uses cookies with the following names to monitor visitors to our website, so that we can improve the experience for all users:_utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz. Read more about the Google Analytics privacy policy <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>

## How you can manage your privacy

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

## Site search

Our website search functionality is powered by Drupal. Search queries and results are logged anonymously to help us improve our website and search functionality. No user-specific data is collected.

## Links to other websites

We feature links to external websites and have reciprocal website links with appropriate organisations and contribute content to other relevant sites. This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.

## How we protect your privacy

We do not engage in any marketing or advertising practices using cookies which identify you or your computer and we never share personally identifiable information with those outside of our organisation.

We share anonymous website usage information with Google Analytics as listed above.

### Disclosure of your information:

We may disclose information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is:

  * reasonably necessary to comply with the law
  * necessary to protect our rights and those of our users
